都柏林举世闻名，
Dublin might be world famous,
但你知道它正面临一场危机吗？
but did you know it's facing a bit of a crisis?
这座美丽的城市每年迎来数百万游客，
The fair city welcomes millions of visitors every year
来此参观古堡、大教堂，
to see its castles, cathedrals,
当然还有那家著名的吉尼斯啤酒馆。
and of course, the Guinness Storehouse.
美国游客到处都是。
All the Americans are all over here.
老天，我太喜欢这里了，
Oh my god, I love this.
我爱爱尔兰。
I love Ireland.
他们正在做的……
They're doing my
这里是一片历史与文化积淀深厚的土地。
It's an area rich in history and culture.
然而，景点固然令人叹为观止，前往这些地方的过程却并不那么顺畅。
But while its attractions are a sight to behold, getting to them isn't exactly straightforward.
有谁能解释一下，为什么这里的交通如此糟糕？
Can anybody explain to me why the traffic is so bad?
45分钟的路程能变成3小时的煎熬，
A 45-minute journey can turn into a 3-hour journey.
每天在路上花2到3个半甚至4个小时，
So, you're looking at about
这是家常便饭。
2 and 3 and 1/2 and 4 hours on the road
every day.
在早晚高峰期间，
During our peak rush hours,
整个路网的平均车速约为每小时11公里。
the average speed across the network is about 11 km an hour.
>> 每小时11公里。>> 每小时11公里。
>> 11 km an hour. >> 11 km an hour.
如果你是个跑步达人，跑步甚至比开车还快。
If you're a fast runner, you'll actually run quicker than that.
都柏林的人口自世纪之交以来增长了近三分之一，
Dublin's population has grown by nearly a third since the turn of the century,
但城市的交通基础设施
but its travel infrastructure
却完全没有跟上这个步伐。
has in no way kept pace.
它如今是全球第11大最拥堵的城市，
It's now the 11th most congested city in the world,
而且每年排名都在上升。
and each year it's climbing the rankings.
2025年，作为都柏林的一名司机，
In 2025, as a driver in Dublin,
你一年中平均要在堵车中
you'll have sat in traffic delays
耗掉整整95个令人崩溃的小时。
for an average of 95 mind-numbing hours across the year.
这段时间，你可以打80多场盖尔式足球比赛，
In that time, you could play more than 80 Gaelic football matches
或者把《神父泰德》完整看九遍。
or watch the entirety of Father Ted nine times through.
顺便说一句，这比2024年的延误时间增加了17%，
And by the way, that's a 17% increase in delay times on 2024
比2023年增加了32%。
and a 32% increase on 2023.
简而言之，在都柏林出行简直是一场噩梦，而且情况还在持续恶化。
Put simply, traveling around Dublin is a nightmare, and the situation's getting worse.
说得对吧，你明白我的意思吗？
It's actually a good point, you know what I'm trying to say?
到2040年，拥堵带来的经济损失预计
By 2040, the economic costs associated with congestion are expected
将高达每年15亿欧元。哎哟。
to hit a whopping 1.5 billion euros every year. Ouch.
问题是，政府本应通过大规模的基础设施投资来
The thing is, the government was supposed to be sorting this with a massive investment into infrastructure,
解决这一问题，但官员们却在"公共交通与道路投资比例二比一"的政策上
but officials have U-turned on a policy
出尔反尔。
to spend on a ratio of two to one between public transport and roads.
各方迫切呼吁改善交通，因为这个问题
There are desperate calls for a travel fix because the problem
不仅影响着每个人的日常生活，对外国投资者来说也是一个警示信号。
not only affects people personally,
but it's a bit of a red flag for foreign investors.
交通基础设施匮乏，实在不是什么好的宣传名片。
A lack of travel infrastructure isn't a great advertisement.
近30年来，爱尔兰一直在承诺建设一条迫切需要的地铁，
For nearly 30 years, Ireland has teased a desperately needed metro
以解决拥堵噩梦。
to tackle its congestion nightmare.
但实际上，却没有真正向建设迈出任何实质性的步伐。
But, without really making any proper inroads towards building it.
随着都柏林的交通问题日益恶化，
And with Dublin's travel problem getting worse and worse,
究竟有没有人在认真解决这座城市的问题？
what the hell's being done to fix this city?
>> >> 爱尔兰并非不知道
>> >> It's not like Ireland doesn't know
都柏林的交通已是一场噩梦。
that Dublin needs help with its travel horror show.
世纪之交，政府作为"交通21计划"的一部分，提出了建设一条崭新地铁的宏大设想。
At the turn of the century, the government proposed a flashy new metro
as part of its Transport 21 initiative.
该计划拟斥资340亿欧元对爱尔兰的交通基础设施进行全面升级，
The plan was to spend 34 billion euros modernizing Ireland's travel infrastructure.
其中包括一条从圣斯蒂芬绿地到都柏林机场、再延伸至斯沃兹的地下铁路线。
And that included an underground train line from St. Stephen's Green
to Dublin Airport and then continuing to Swords.
我今天可以确认的是，
What I am confirming today is that by 2007,
到2007年，机场连接线将建成，
we will have the airport link done
因为这已被列为政府的优先事项。
because that has been identified now as a government priority.
你看，都柏林已经远远落后了。
You see, Dublin has fallen well behind.
除了拥堵困境，如果你曾试图前往都柏林机场，
Beyond its congestion dilemma, if you've tried traveling to Dublin Airport,
你一定清楚
you'll be more than aware that
那里根本没有任何铁路连接。
there's no rail access whatsoever.
看到M50公路上那排车龙了吗，
If you saw all the cars queuing up going out the M50,
我们今天早上刚从戈尔韦过来。
we're just coming up from Galway this morning.
在我看来，爱尔兰根本就没有像样的公共交通系统。
There's there's no transport system in Ireland as far as I can see.
它实际上是欧洲最后几个没有直达机场火车的首都城市之一。
It's actually one of the last European capitals without a direct train to its airport.
你只能打出租车、搭便车，或者坐公共汽车，
You've got to take a taxi, get a lift, or jump on the bus,
对于一座这规模的城市来
which seems a bit ridiculous for a city
说，这实在有些荒谬。
of this scale.
2005年，"北部地铁"这一方案正式走入公众视野。
In 2005, Metro North as it was known was formally thrown into the limelight.
它被视为将都柏林带入21世纪的重要途径。
It was seen as way to drag Dublin into the 21st century.
这个项目甚至获得了规划许可，这是个历史性的时刻，
This thing even gained planning permission, which was a a huge moment.
某种程度上代表着
It kind of represented this big new dawn
都柏林人迎来了全新的黎明。
for the people of Dublin.
然而到了2011年，一切都成了泡影。
But by 2011, it had become a non-starter.
爱尔兰经济曾被视为欧洲最稳定的经济体之一。
The Irish economy was considered one of the most stable in Europe.
>> 是欧洲最繁荣的经济体之一。
>> One of the most booming economies in Europe.
>> 它有了一个名字——凯尔特之虎。
>> It became known as the Celtic Tiger.
>> 然后，金融危机来了。
>> Then the financial crisis hit.
凯尔特之虎已死。
The Celtic Tiger is dead.
>> 官方宣布，该国已陷入衰退。
>> Officially, the country is now in recession.
>> 爱尔兰究竟发生了什么？
>> What's going on in Ireland?
贪婪，贪婪，还是贪婪。当时的政府还在极力否认救助的说法。
Greed, greed, and more But the then government rubbished talk about a bailout.
这只是无稽之谈吗？就是无稽之谈。
Is it just total fiction? It is fiction.
三天后，央行宣布救助计划已成定局。
Three days later, Central Bank said there would be a bailout.
我们当时有一届愚蠢的政府，监管机构在监管上严重失职。
We had a stupid government with a regulator that was asleep at the wheel.
当然，还有那些银行家。
And of course, above all, bankers.
爱尔兰的纳税人急需一个答案，请现在就给我们一个交代。
The taxpayers at home in Ireland who would like to have some answers. Please now.
好了，非常感谢您。
Okay, thank you very much.
你是个麻烦制造者，因为没有人相信……
You're a liability because nobody believes
这是上世纪90年代初以来首次出现福利排队的情况。
Welfare queues are forming for the first time since the early '90s.
老天啊。
Jeez, man.
这、这、这简直是一场闹剧。
This is this is this is a joke.
我感觉到，大家似乎有一点点不满情绪。
So, I'm sensing a a wee bit of discontent.
您说得太对了，先生。
You are indeed, sir.
>> >> 随着全球经济衰退导致资金告急，
>> >> As the money dried up due to the global recession,
北部地铁被一再推后，在优先级列表上越滑越远。
Metro North slipped further and further down the priority list.
此后，各种修订版本相继出炉。
Various iterations have since followed.
2018年，一项更新后的计划让都柏林市民燃起了希望：
In 2018, an updated plan offered hope that Dubliners could get around
或许可以通过地下铁路在2027年前出行。
the city via an underground train line by 2027.
但到了2021年，工地连一锹土都没动，
But come 2021, with no spades in the ground,
政府却表示，那个时间节点……你们听听这段话。
the government said the timeline was, well, just take listen to this.
那个目标从来就不现实，说实话吧。
That was never likely to be to be achievable, I'll be honest.
而且这个项目的预算估算，也远高于最终可能的实际花费。
And the budget forecast for this is also much more than the likely final outcome.
哦，天哪。
Oh, jeez.
重——>> 【笑声】>> 认真的吗？
Re- >> [laughter] >> Really?
尽管他们说的是实话——
And while they were right, because that would be next year,
因为按计划那应该是明年开工，而到那时工程根本还没开始——
and no groundwork had started yet,
但一开始为什么要设置那些根本不可能实现的截止日期呢？
why set unrealistic deadlines to begin with?
建设工作本应在2025年之前启动，
Construction should then have gotten underway by 2025,
但最新的地铁设计
but the latest metro designs didn't gain planning permission
直到去年10月才获得规划许可。
until October last year.
由于爱尔兰在建设地铁这件事上一再受挫，
And because of the twisting nature of Ireland's so far failed attempts to build a metro,
市民们对这件事
the city's residents are somewhat skeptical
能否真正实现已经相当悲观。
it'll ever happen.
我觉得他们就应该立刻动手，把这个该死的东西建起来。
I think they should get on and build the bloody thing.
>> 但政府值得信任吗？
>> But can the government be trusted?
如果你出生的那天正好是地铁原定开通的日子，
If you were born the day that the metro was initially due to open,
等到地铁真正开通时，你已经可以投票了。
you'd be able to vote by the time it does actually open.
尽管地铁有望将进城的通勤时间缩短一半以上，
Even though it could cut travel time to the city by more than half,
但都柏林市民曾经被地铁承诺伤过心，
Dubliners have been stung by promises of an underground rail line
对此信心不足。
in the past.
所以，大家普遍持悲观态度。
So, confidence is pretty low.
就连 The B1M 自己的爱尔兰人、才华横溢的视频剪辑师吉姆·凯西也远非乐观。
Even the B1M's own Irishman and video editor extraordinaire Jim Casey is far from convinced.
话虽如此，最新的计划确实给人带来了谨慎乐观的理由。
With all that being said, the latest plans give real reason for careful optimism.
政府在最近一次预算中承诺拨款
Government have committed in the the last budget
20亿欧元，用于
2 billion euro for um uh for metro
推进地铁项目。
to to proceed.
所以，政府以及支持、规划和推进地铁建设的
So, governments and the agencies that are supporting and and building building and delivering metro
各机构，都在以这条基础设施必将建成的
are proceeding as if this piece of infrastructure
信念向前推进。
is going to happen.
我们正在招募人才，
We're hiring people,
招标文件已经准备就绪，即将面向市场引入联合体来交付我们的地铁项目。
the tender documents have been put together to bring consortia to the city to deliver our metro.
都柏林地铁第二次获得规划许可。
For the second time, planning permission has been granted for a metro in Dublin.
尽管在线路走向和施工方式上经历了无数耗时的讨论，
And while it's taken countless time-consuming discussions
但这在某种程度上也说得通。
about where the route should go and how it should be constructed, that almost makes sense.
这条地铁一改再改，设计了又设计。
This metro has been designed, redesigned, and redesigned again.
不断推敲各种线路方案，
And developing various iterations of the route,
哪怕最终难逃被搁置的命运，本身也是一项极为耗时的工作。
even if they're inevitably cast aside, is a time-consuming task.
但其实大可不必如此。
But it doesn't have to be.
话说我最近一直在用 Round Design 的全能 CAD 软件，在都柏林市中心给自己设计梦想之家——
While I've been using RoundDesigns all-in-one CAD software to create my dream home
顺便说一句，各位，我大概只需要赚到一兆次 YouTube 播放量就能付得起房款……
right smack in the middle of Dublin,
which by the way, guys, I only need like a trillion YouTube video views
顺便说一句，各位，我大概只需要赚到一兆次 YouTube 播放量就能付得起房款……
to pay
……而这个平台其实也是任何类型项目的理想协作工具，
for, this platform is actually the ideal workmate for any type of project,
包括——举个例子——一条全新的大型地铁线路。
including, for example, a massive new metro line.
Round Design 是一款专为设计师和建筑师打造的全网页端次世代工具。
Round Design is a fully web-based next generation tool built for designers and architects.
比如说，你想设计将来可能驶过都柏林的那批时髦新列车车厢。
So, say you want to design the swanky new train carriages
that could run through Dublin.
你可以导入行业标准文件，也可以从零开始创建自己的设计。
You can import industry standard files or create your own design from scratch.
但如果你在现有软件库中数以万计的
But, what if you can't find, for instance, a train seat from the thousands
CAD 构件里，就是找不到你想要的那把列车座椅，该怎么办？
of thousands of CAD blocks in the pre-existing software libraries?
没问题，Round Design 内置了一款 AI 工具，可以将你的图片矢量化。
Well, Round Design has an AI tool that can vectorize your images.
举个例子，我设计的列车车厢里摆了一张转角沙发和一个深蹲架。
As an example, my train carriage features a corner sofa and a squat rack.
而且因为一切都集成在同一平台上，我可以在不切换工具的情况下，完成设计、编辑、存档，
And because it's all in one, I can design, edit, document,
再到展示提案，一气呵成。
and then present my proposal without having to faff around switching tools.
想象一下，再也不用在多款软件之间来回传输文件了，省心省力。
Just imagine, no more wasting time transferring files between multiple different softwares.
不论你是正在规划下一条伟大地铁线路的
Whether you're an urban planner designing the next great metro line,
城市规划师，还是像我一样，只想在都柏林设计一套豪华顶层公寓，
or like me, you just want to draw up a swanky Irish penthouse,
都可以通过视频简介中的链接
you can try Round Design for free using the link in the description
或扫描屏幕上的二维码，免费试用 Round Design。
or by scanning the QR code on screen now.
好了，让我们回到都柏林地铁的
Now, let's get back to Dublin's metro
话题，因为这件事看来终于有了一些实质进展。
because it looks like they might actually be getting somewhere.
>> >> 鉴于这是这个国家的第一条地铁，
>> >> Given this is the country's first ever metro,
相关部门显然非常看重把事情做对。
authorities are obviously keen to get it right.
在这样一个项目上花费数十亿欧元，最后发现线路选错了，那将是一场灾难——
Spending billions on a project like this and then getting the route wrong would be disastrous,
尤其是整个过程已经耗费了太多时间，
especially when it's already taken quite a lot of time
本来就已经是一团糟。
and has already been a bit of a debacle.
说实话，我觉得大家只希望政府
Honestly, I think people just want the government
和相关部门雷厉风行，把事情落实，
and the authorities to get on with it
别再说废话了。
and deliver it and stop talking about it.
上次方案公布时，
When it was announced the last time,
有一位动物学研究员说，
there was a a researcher in zoology that basically said,
"我们讨论地铁、准备建地铁的时间，
"The time that we've been talking about the metro and to construct a metro,
一只蜗牛早就从都柏林市中心
a snail could have gone from Dublin city center,
爬过了机场，
I passed the airport, and do the whole line
把整条线路全爬完了。"
based upon how long it's taken us to get to where we are right now."
所以我认为，现在资金到位了，
So, I think right now, the money
雄心在，支持在。
is there, the ambition is there, the support is there.
如果不是现在，那要等到什么时候？
So, if not now, when?
等了这么久，感觉这个周而复始的循环可能永远不会结束。
After waiting so long already, it probably feels like this merry-go-round could continue forever.
但你可以问问多伦多市民，他们等了将近20年才等到埃格林顿越城线开工；
But, ask Torontonians who waited nearly 20 years for work to start on Eglinton Crosstown
也可以问问塞萨洛尼基市——那座城市等了整整一个世纪才迎来地铁——
or the city of Thessaloniki which waited a century for its metro
你就会明白，这类项目往往需要漫长的等待，
and you'll realize that these projects can take an absolute age to happen
然后突然之间，整座城市就变成了一个大工地。
and then all of a sudden the city turns into a work site.
话说到这里，建设都柏林地铁线的合同招标工作
And with that said the bidding process
其实已经正式启动。
for contracts to build Dublin MetroLink has actually started.
计划是将都柏林南北两端与机场相连，
The plan is to link the north and south of Dublin
途经16个站点
connecting the airport
贯穿城市两端。
with each end of the city via 16 stations.
当然，好事向来没有便宜货。
Inevitably as with all good things it's not going to come cheap.
线路将从查尔蒙特出发，
The line will stretch nearly 19 kilometers from Charlemont
途经三所大学、学校和医院，
passing through three different universities schools hospitals
绵延近19公里，
going all the way up to Swords
一路延伸至北都柏林郡的斯沃兹——这是整个爱尔兰增长最快的地区之一。
in North County Dublin one of the fastest growing areas in all of Ireland.
而实现这一切，
And all of that
需要付出高达95亿欧元的代价。
will come with a whopping price tag of 9.5 billion euros.
换算一下，这相当于每公里约5亿欧元。
For context that's around 500 million euros per kilometer.
尽管被认为可能性不大，爱尔兰交通部
While cited as unlikely
还是表示，该项目费用或许会达到令人咋舌的230亿欧元。
the Department for Transport said the project could reach a staggering 23 billion euros.
如果真是如此，其每公里造价
That would give it a cost per kilometer
将与纽约第二大道地铁相当。
similar to that of New York's Second Avenue Subway.
都柏林地铁线有可能成为
Dublin MetroLink could become one of the most expensive
史上造价最高昂的地下铁路之一。
underground train lines of all time.
那么，关键问题来了：为什么？
So the big question is why?
为什么爱尔兰的第一条地铁如此昂贵？
Why is Ireland's first metro so expensive
尤其是考虑到早期方案的
especially when you consider that an early iteration
估算仅为30亿欧元。
of the plan came with an estimate of just three billion euros.
通货膨胀当然是因素之一，
Well inflation certainly plays a part
但很大一部分成本来自施工工法的选择。
but a lot of the cost comes with the construction methodology.
早期设计方案主张大量采用
Early designs called for Dublin's metro to be largely delivered
明挖回填法——这在理论上是最理想的方式。
using cut and cover which is kind of the ideal.
你从地面向下开挖到目标深度，
You excavate from the surface down to your desired depth
搭建结构，然后再回填覆土。
construct your structure and then backfill on top of it.
明挖回填法性价比高，也比深层地下作业省力得多。
Cut and cover is pretty cost effective and less intense than trudging deep underground.
不需要挖太深，
You're not having to dig too far down,
也就不用应对深处的重大工程挑战。
which means no serious engineering at depths.
或许最重要的是，你不需要买或租这种东西。
And perhaps most importantly, you haven't got to buy or hire one of these.
如果你看过我们频道超过5分钟的视频，
If you spent any more than 5 minutes watching one of our videos,
那你大概已经认识 TBM，也就是隧道掘进机了。
then you're probably going to recognize TBMs or tunnel boring machines.
它们从地面深处掘进，穿透岩石和土壤，开凿出
They dig deep below the surface, carving through rock and soil to create, well,
一条条隧道——而且一点都不"无聊"（far from boring）。
tunnels, and they're far from boring.
与明挖法相比，使用 TBM 的造价要高出许多。
It's a whole lot more expensive than the alternative.
尽管如此，最新方案还是大量采用了这种设备。
Nevertheless, the latest schematics make regular use of them.
原因是，明挖回填法对交通和市民的影响极其巨大。
You see, cut and cover is incredibly disruptive.
道路必须关闭或改为单行，
Roads have to be closed or converted to one way
时间动辄数周乃至数月。
for weeks and even months on end.
都柏林的魅力之一，正是那些风景如画的狭窄街道。
One of the appeals of Dublin is those picturesque narrow streets.
但在这座全球第11大最拥堵的城市里，
But in the 11th most congested city on the planet,
多一分混乱就多一分麻烦。
more chaos than necessary is just asking for trouble.
简而言之，隧道掘进法可以将施工对城市的冲击降到最低，
In short, tunnel boring limits the chaos,
这在如此密集的城市里至关重要。
which is crucial when you're working in a dense city like this.
事实上，方案已经作出了一些调整。
And actually, the plan's been changed a bit.
现在，列车将穿行于单管隧道
So, the trains are now going to travel through one single bore tunnel
之中，而非最初规划的双管系统。
rather than the originally planned twin bore system.
这样做的目的是减少施工量，
And the idea of that is to cut down on work
并最终压缩部分成本。
and ultimately some cost.
明挖回填法将仅限于特定的浅层路段
Cut and cover's going to be limited to specific shallow sections
和沿线的地面站。
and surface stations along the route.
例如奥康内尔街和圣斯蒂芬绿地。
For instance, at O'Connell Street and St. Stephen's Green.
在遗址附近，将挖设深挖站台箱——基本上是地下的大型结构壳体，
Deep station boxes, basically like a large shell underground
用来容纳
to house the station structure,
站台结构。
are going to be dug into the earth near heritage sites.
隧道掘进必须尽量减少，以保护这些建筑的地基。
Tunneling has got to be minimized to protect the foundations of those buildings.
目前，沿线隧道直径将达9.5米，
Now, tunnels along the route are going to be 9.5 m in diameter
最深处可达地下30米。
and reach depths of up to 30 m.
在整个施工过程中，将对地面沉降和振动进行持续监测，
And throughout the process, settlement and vibration are going to be monitored
以确保地基保持稳定。
to make sure the ground remains stable.
>> >> 所有这些工作，
>> >> Now, all of that work
都是建设这条迫切需要的基础设施所必须经历的。
is necessary to build a much-needed piece of infrastructure.
对于我这样的建筑爱好者来说，
And for construction fans like myself,
这是一个值得持续关注和跟进的超酷项目。
it's a pretty cool project to be able to watch,
follow, and check in on.
但这个过程的破坏性极强：
But, the process is incredibly disruptive.
隧道掘进、现有交通线路改道、
The tunneling, the rerouting of existing travel options,
噪音、扬尘……罄竹难书。
the noise, the dust, the list goes on.
我想说的是，
I guess what I'm trying to say
都柏林地铁线在让一切变好之前，
is that the Dublin MetroLink is going to make
会先让一切变得更糟。
things a whole lot worse before it makes them any better.
这条地铁线穿越城市核心，
This metro line is going through the heart of the city,
在城区和居民区地下穿行。
driving under and through urban areas and residential spaces.
除了必要的道路封闭（这本身就会加剧拥堵）之外，
And beyond some necessary but congestion-causing road closures,
部分隧道施工还将24小时不间断进行。
some of the tunneling work is set to be carried out around the clock.
每当隧道掘进机经过某个区域，周边居民要忍受大约3周的噪音；
As a TBM approaches an area, there'll be about 3 weeks worth of noise,
掘进机离开时，
and then another 3 weeks worth of noise
又要再扛3周。
as it leaves again.
这意味着不可避免地要承受长达6周的施工噪音。
That's 6 weeks of unavoidable construction noise.
说实话，隧道掘进机并不是什么低调的设备。
And in truth, TBMs aren't exactly subtle.
别忘了，这些隧道
You've got to remember that these tunnels
正在被直接挖掘于办公场所、公共公园和居民住宅的正下方。
are being dug directly beneath workplaces, public parks, and people's homes.
那想去附近公园散散心？
So, what about escaping to a local park for some peace and quiet?
没那么容易。圣斯蒂芬绿地——都柏林最受欢迎的绿地，
Well, not so fast. 20% of the city's most popular green space,
其中20%的面积将在施工期间关闭。
St. Stephen's Green, is going to be closed during construction.
距市中心15分钟车程的
And Albert College Park, 15 minutes from the city center,
阿尔伯特学院公园，绿树成荫、草木葱郁，还有一处儿童游乐场，
flush with trees, green space, and a playground,
但这里将成为一个强制性救援竖井的施工中心。
is going to be the center of a mandatory intervention shaft.
隧道必须沿线每隔一段距离设置逃生通道
You see, tunnels have to offer escape
和通风设施。
routes and ventilation at pretty regular points along the route.
举个例子，如果在一条3000米长的隧道
For instance, if you had a 3,000-m long tunnel
中发生火灾，救援人员将面临严峻挑战，
and a fire broke out, emergency services
而被困的乘客
would have a serious battle to reach commuters
将在极度缺氧的环境中苦苦挣扎。
who'd be suffering with very little fresh air.
欧盟要求逃生间距不得超过1000米，
The EU calls for these intervals to be less than 1,000 m apart.
而这正是问题所在。
And therein lies the problem.
连接柯林斯大道
The section of track that runs underneath
和格里菲斯公园之间的隧道段长达近1500米。
the area between Collins Avenue and Griffith Park is nearly 1,500 m.
这意味着不符合欧盟规定，
I.E., it gets a big shake of the head from the EU,
因此必须在距离这两个站点不超过
and that's why an intervention shaft
1公里的地方设置救援竖井。
has to be created no more than a kilometer from either of these stations.
阿尔伯特学院公园是首选地点。
Albert College Park is the destination of choice,
然而，都柏林市民一边忍受拥堵道路和关闭公园，
but while Dubliners are battling congested roads and closed-off parks,
出行困境恐怕还将进一步延伸。
I'm afraid the travel problem is going to stretch even further.
新建铁路线的讽刺之处在于，它将临时
The irony of building a new train line is that it's going to temporarily
关闭部分现有地面线路。
close some of the existing above-ground routes.
通勤者将不得不另寻出路——
Commuters are going to have to find other ways to travel,
改乘改道后的列车、公共汽车，
whether that's on redirected trains, on buses,
或者，深吸一口气，重新开车上路。
or take a deep breath, by getting back into their cars.
西部通勤线将关闭近2年，
Sections of the Western Commuter Line are going to be shut for nearly 2 years,
西南通勤线也将面临
and the Southwestern Commuter Line is going to face closures
长达5个月的封闭，这绝对不会好受。
for up to 5 months, which is not going to be pretty.
当然，这并不是专门针对爱尔兰施工方式的刁难。
Now, this isn't some agenda against Ireland's approach to construction.
全球任何一座密集型城市，若要在街道上开凿明挖隧道
If any dense city anywhere in the world were to start building open tunnels in the streets
或在市中心修建新站点，
or constructing new stations in the middle of its urban center,
都必然面临空间问题。
there would, of course, be a space issue.
也不可能把都柏林的大片区域
And it's not like large sections of Dublin
全部封锁起来施工。
can be closed down for this work to take place.
这个项目必须与城市日常生活和谐共存。
This project has got to coexist around everyday life in this city.
但是，考虑到全球大多数地铁项目的进展规律，
But, given how most of these metro builds go around the world,
以及爱尔兰
and the fact that Ireland
是第一次做这件事，
is going to be doing this for the first time,
如果这座美丽的城市在相当一段时间内变成一个大工地，
don't be surprised if the fair city is a work site
请不要感到意外。
for quite a while.
当然，这绝对不意味着这件事应该再次被搁置。
Although, that absolutely doesn't mean that this thing should be shelved yet again.
这些是我们国家关键的基础设施项目，
These projects are critical pieces of infrastructure um for our country,
无法推进这些项目，简直是一种拖累。
and not being able to deliver them is crippling.
拖累我们的城市、拖累我们的基础设施、
Crippling our cities, crippling our infrastructure,
拖累我们推进住房和交通建设的能力，
crippling our ability to be able to deliver the housing and transport,
也让我们的气候目标无从实现。
and meet our climate goals.
希望这一次，常识能够战胜一切，
Hopefully, on this one, uh common sense will prevail,
项目得以顺利推进，
and and the project will go ahead,
因为它将对我们的城市产生深远而根本的影响。
because it will have such a fundamental impact upon our city.
但要享受这条线路带来的红利，施工必须真正启动。
But, to see the benefits of the line, construction work actually needs to begin.
爱尔兰交通部长达拉·奥布莱恩此前表示，
The Minister for Transportation, Dara O'Brien, previously said
计划于2027年破土动工，希望一切顺利。
that the aim is to break ground in 2027. So, fingers crossed.
如果你正在2027年或更晚的时候
If you're watching this in 2027 or later,
看这个视频，地铁还没有开工的话，那我们真的很遗憾。
and it still hasn't started, then we're really sorry to hear that.
除了缓解都柏林拥堵这个
Beyond the obvious benefits Dublin MetroLink should have on easing congestion here,
显而易见的益处，都柏林地铁线还必须在财务上站得住脚。
the line has also got to stack up financially.
我们知道它造价不菲，
We know it's going to cost a pretty penny,
但爱尔兰交通部
but early estimates in 2022 from the Department of Transport suggested
2022年的早期估算显示，在地铁运营的60年间，
that the Irish economy would receive about 13.7 billion euros over a 60-year period
爱尔兰经济将因此获得约137亿欧元的收益。
due to the Metro's existence.
这意味着，
What that means,
如果项目造价真的飙升到那个不太可能的230亿欧元大关，
if the project somehow skyrockets to that unlikely 23 billion euro construction mark,
那……就祈祷它不要发生吧。
well, let's just hope that doesn't happen.
这不会是一段舒适的旅程。
It's not going to be a comfortable journey.
建设这条线路势必引发不少麻烦。
Building this routes will undoubtedly cause more than a few headaches.
尽管都柏林人的怀疑情绪依然存在，但事情似乎终于要真正发生了。
While a healthy dose of skepticism remains among Dubliners, it does seem to finally be happening.
这座城市等待解决出行困境
This city's waited patiently for an answer to its travel woes
已将近30年，现在，答案或许终于要来了。
for nearly 30 years, and it looks like it might finally be about to get it.
本视频由 Rayon Design 赞助播出。
This video was sponsored by Rayon Design.
如果你是专业室内设计师或建筑师，
Don't forget that if you're a professional interior designer or an architect,
别忘了通过视频简介中的链接
you're going to want to check out Rayon Design
免费试用 Rayon Design。
by yourself for free at the link in the description.
一如既往，各位，如果你喜欢这个视频
And as always, guys, if you enjoyed this video
并希望持续关注这个专注于建筑施工的权威视频频道，
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
请记得订阅 The B1M。
make sure you subscribe to the B1M.